AMMAR SAMIR FARG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER PHP LARAVEL BACKEND WEB DEVELOPER

DEAR HIRING MANAGER,
AND TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN,

I am writing to express my interest in the position of back-end Web Developer at your company. I have the Experience in the software engineering industry, website development.

I am confident that I have the skills and experience to be a valuable asset to your company. as Web Developer.

I am a highly motivated and results-oriented individual who is passionate about technology. and innovation.

I am also a team player who is always willing to go the extra mile to get the job done.

I am eager to learn more about the Web Developer or Backend Developer position at your company. and how I can contribute to your company's success.

I am available for an interview at your earliest convenience.

Thank you for your time and consideration.

AMMAR GAMIR

Thank you for your attention, and I look forward to hearing from you.

SINCERELY,

AMMAR SAMIR FARAG



AMMAR SAMIR FARG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER
PHP LARAVEL BACKEND WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- 201001509214
- amarsamir632@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/ammar-samir-479206250/
- https://github.com/ammar422
- First Address
 Egypt Kafr El-Sheikh Governorate Kafr El-Sheikh City Center
- Second address
 Egypt Cairo-NasrCity

EDUCATION

Computer science bachelor degree

Higher institute of management and information technology 2015 - 2019

Excellent / 95.08%

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native

English secondary

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Organized
- Communication
- Critical thinking
- Teamwork
- Meeting deadlines
- Problem Solving
- Ability to learn new technologies

OBJECTIVE

I seek challenging opportunities where I can fully use my skills for the success of the organization.

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with a great ability to understand and build complex systems and Websites.

And I am Backend WEB developer(PHP Laravel)
with more than one year of experience.
I have knowledge in software engineering In
addition to more than five years of experience
and knowledge in network engineering and
management, design and implementation.
I changed my career path from the field of
networking to programming and web
development because I love challenges and I
also love programming and dealing with code,
whatever the programming language used or
required.

I worked in many different companies on many different projects in my previous field, which gave me experience in communication and working within a team.

I also look forward to developing myself in the field of web development to add the greatest possible value to the organization



AMMAR SAMIR FARG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER
PHP LARAVEL BACKEND WEB DEVELOPER

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Research
WordPress
Project management
Web Development
Softwear design pattern
MVC

HMVC

Python

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

PHP

SQL

Laravel

Git / GitHub

laragon

docker

C++

Agile

Windows Server

Remote Connections

IT and Technical Support

LAN Configuration

WAN Configuration

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Specialist (part-time)

GiroNil company Cairo, Egypt

MAY 2018- OCT 2019

I was working within a team responsible for the safety of users' devices, maintaining them, and making full settings. I was also responsible for network devices and making their settings.

System and Network Administrator (Military service)

General Military Hospital in Alexandria

DEC 2020 - JUN 2022

Operating the hospital's systems in all its departments and making their own settings, as well as ensuring the flow of data through the internal network and linking it to the external network.

network engineer at (NOC) Network Operation Center

<u>Telecom Egypt (WE)</u> *JULY 2022 - september 2023*

Working within a very tight time frame to fix the malfunctions of the institutions involved in some of the company's services, which require high knowledge of network protocols, by receiving the malfunction ticket and processing it on time.

PHP LARAVEL Backend WEB Developer (Remotely Part Time)

Taqnih Saudi Company For Software industry

october 2023 - Until Now

Backend Web Developer
Working as a Laravel developer